A Guide to the Dabney-Jackson Collection, 1716, 1744-1867
Library of Virginia
- T. J. "Stonewall" Jackson Papers 1815-1867 (bulk, 1847-1867) (Box 1-2)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, near Mount Jackson, to Col. S. Bassett French, A. D. C., to Governor [John] Letcher, n. p., 21 March 1862, 97; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Map. "Sketch of the battle at Kernstown, made on the field by two of General Jackson's staff officers, Major Jed Hotchkiss, Chief of Engineers, and Major R. L. Dabney, Chief of Staff," 23 March 1862, 98; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter. Lt. Col. D. A. Langhorne, Head Quarters, 42nd Regt. Virginia Volunteers, n. p., to Col. Jesse Burks, Commanding Brigade, n. p., 23 March 1862, 99; 5 pp. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter. Lieut. Col. Ch[arles] A. Ronald, Head Quarters, 4th Regiment Virginia Volunteers, Camp Buchanan, Virginia, to Capt. R. J. Wingate, n. p., [23 March 1862?], 100; 5 pp. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - List of casualties. "Kernstown." [23 March 1862], 101; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter. Col. J. Q. A. Nadenbousch, Camp at Bartonsville, to Col. T[urner] Ashby and Col. J. W. Allen, n. p., 23 March 1862, 102; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Report of the killed and wounded serving in the Army of the Valley of Virginia in the engagement of the 25th March 1862 [Battle of Kernstown] near Winchester, Virginia., 103; 19 pp.; With summary report signed by Hunter McGuire, Medical Director, Army of Northern Virginia. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter. William H. Morgan, Adjt., 21st Regiment, Virginia Volunteers, n. p., to Lt. Col. John M. Patton, Jr., n. p., 25 March 1862, 104; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter. Capt. D. B. Bridgford, Bivouac near Winchester, Shenandoah County, Virginia, to Capt. R. L. Wilson, A. A. G., n. p., 26 March 1862, 105; 7 pp.; With enclosure: "Report of casualties in the 1st Virginia Battalion, P. A. C. S. in the action near Winchester on the 23rd March 1862." (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter. Col. Turner Ashby, Camp near Woodstock, to Major A. S. Pendleton, A. A. A. G., Army of the Valley, n. p., 26 March 1862, 106; 2 p. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter. Col. Samuel V. Fulkerson, Camp near Mount Jackson, Virginia, to Lieut. A. S. Pendleton, A. A. G., n. p., 26 March 1862, 107; 6 pp. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter. J. H. Dupuy, Acting Adjutant, Camp near Mount Jackson, to Col. Samuel V. Fulkerson, n. p., 26 March 1862, 108; 4 pp.; Probably forwarded to Gen. T. J. Jackson. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter. Lt. Col. John M. Patton, Jr., Camp near Mount Jackson, to Col. Jesse Burks, commanding 3rd Brigade, n. p., 26 March 1862, 109; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letter. Capt. Joseph Carpenter, Head Quarters, Carpenter's Battery, to Gen. [____], n. p., 27 March 1862, 110; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter. Col. Jesse S. Burks, Head Quarters, 3rd Brigade, Camp near Woodstock, Virginia, to Capt. A. S. Pendleton, A. A. A. Genl. V. D., n. p., 27 March 1862, 111; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter. Col. A. C. Cummings, Camp Buchanan near Mount Jackson, to R. J. Wingate, A. A. G., n. p., 27 March 1862, 112; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter. Lt. Col. A. J. Grigsby, Head Quarters, 27th Regt. Virginia Volunteers, Camp [____], Virginia, to Capt. R. J. Wingate, A. A. G., n. p., 27 March 1862, 113; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter. Capt. William McLaughlin, Commanding Rockbridge Artillery, Camp Buchanan, to Capt. R. J. Wingate, A. A. G., n. p., 27 March 1862, 114; 6 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter. Col. W. H. Harmon, Head Quarters, 5th Regt., Virginia Volunteers, n. p., to Capt. R. J. Wingate, A. A. G., n. p., 27 March 1862, 115; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter. Capt. James H. Waters, Camp Buchanan, to Adj. Gen. R. J. Wingate, n. p., 28 March 1862, 116; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "List of casualties in first Brigade in action near Kernstown, Virginia, on 23 March 1862," 30 March 1862, 117; 2 pp.; Recorded by Brig. Gen. R. B. Garnett, Camp Buchanan, Virginia. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Field report of the 37th and 23rd Regiments, Virginia Volunteers, commanded by Col. Samuel V. Fulkerson in the late engagement near Winchester, Virginia [Kernstown], on the 23rd March 1862, 1 April 1862, 118; 8 pp.; Written at Camp near Mount Jackson. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter. Maj. O. B. Funsten, Camp near Hawkinstown, to Col. Turner Ashby, n. p., 7 April 1862, 119; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letter. Lt. Col. John M. Patton, Jr., Head Quarters, 21st Regt. Virginia Volunteers, n. p., to Col. John A. Campbell, n. p., 7 April 1862, 120; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Battle reports. Ordered by T. J. Jackson of J. W. Allen and Colonel Ashby for tha Battle at Kernstown, 7 April 1862, 120a; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, near Mount Jackson, to Gen. S[amuel Cooper, n. p., 14 April 1862, 121; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter. W. H. Taylor, Headquarters, Richmond, to Gen. T. J. Jackson, Mount Jackson, 16 April 1862, 122; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter. S. Bassett French, [Aide-de-camp to Gov. John Letcher], Richmond, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 16 April 1862, 123; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter. Gen. R. E. Lee, Richmond, to Gen. T. J. Jackson, Commanding Valley District, n. p., 25 April 1862, 124; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter. Gen. R. E. Lee, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Swift Run Gap, 29 April 1862, 125; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter. Gen. R. E. Lee, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Swift Run Gap, 1 May 1862, 126; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Staunton, to Maj. W. H. Taylor, n. p., 5 May 1862, 127; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Staunton, to Maj. Gen. F[rancis] H. Smith, Superintendant, Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, 6 May 1862, 128; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter. [____], Richmond, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 9 May 1862, 129; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Proclamation. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, near Franklin, to soldiers of the Army of the Valley and North West, 12 May 1862, 130; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter. Gen. J. E. Johnston, Cross Roads, New Kent County, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 12 May 1862, 131; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter. R. S. Ewell, n. p., to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 13 May 1862, 132; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter. R. S. Ewell, n. p., to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 13 May 1862, 133; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter. A. R. Boteler, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 16 May 1862, 134; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter. [Gen. J. E. Johnston?], near Richmond, to [____], n. p., 18 May 1862, 135; 1 p.; Bears notation "after reading this send it to Gen. Jackson." (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter. Gen. J. E. Johnston, near Richmond, to Maj. Gen. [R. S.] Ewell, n. p., 18 May 1862, 136; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter. J. E. Johnston, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 21 May 1862, 137; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter. 25 May 1862, 138; 2 pp.; Letter of A. S. Pendleton touching order given Brig. Gen. George H. Stuart at Winchester. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. R. S. Ewell, Head Quarters, 3rd Division, New Market, to Major R. L. Dabney, A. A. G., Department of the Valley, n. p., 4 June 1862, 139; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, 2nd Army Corps, Brown's Gap, to Maj. T. G. Rhett, n. p., 10 June 1862, 140; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, P. A. C. S., Head Quarters, Valley District, to Gen. John Shields, U. S. A., n. p., 11 June 1862, 141; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - General Orders No. [__]. Headquarters, 24 June 1862, 142; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter. By command of Gen. [R. E.] Lee, R. H. Chilton, A. A. G., Dabbs House, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, 25 June 1862, 143; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letter. Brig. Gen. Charles S. Winder, Head Quarters, 1st Brigade, V. D., n. p., to Capt. A. S. Pendleton, A. A. G., Head Quarters, V. D., n. p., 9 July 1862, 144; 9 pp. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, to Col. R. H. Chilton, n. p., August 1862, 145; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper clipping. Reminiscences of the 2nd Virginia Cavalry, n. d., 146; 2 pp.; Concerns the Battle of Boteler's Ford. Reprinted in an unidentified newspaper from the Amherst Enterprise. Filed as 19 September 1862. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Charges and specifications proferred by Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson against Maj. Gen. A. P. Hill, n. d., 147; 2 pp.; Filed as 24 September 1862. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letter. Col. Edward L. Thomas, n. p., to [____], n. p., 24 September 1862, 148; 2 pp.; Re: the arrest of A. P. Hill. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Endorsement on Gen. A. P. Hill's report of the Battle of Cedar Run, n. d., 149; 2 pp.; Probably in the handwriting of T. J. Jackson. Filed as 24 September 1862. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Memorandum. Pertaining to the conduct of Maj. Gen. A. P. Hill at the Battle of Cedar Run, n. d., 150; 4 pp.; Filed as 24 September 1862. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Endorsements. 24 and 26 September 1862, 151; 2 pp.; Of Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson and Gen. R. E. Lee in re: the arrest of Gen. A. P. Hill. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Commission. To T[homas] J. Jackson as Lieutenant General in the Provisional Army of the Confederate States, 11 October 1862, 152; Signed by George W. Randolph, Secretary of War. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter. Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, to Maj. Gen. A. P. Hill, n. p., 10 November 1862, 153; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter. [P. McCormick], n. p., to Dr. Hunter, n. p., 11 November 1862, 154; 1 p.; Incomplete. The typewritten list furnished by Charles W. Dabney states that this letter is "signed by P. McCormick." It appears therefore that the Virginia State Library did not photostat the entire letter. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter. [Gen. R. E. Lee], camp near Culpeper Court House, to Lt. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 18 November 1862, 155; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter. Col. J. D. Imboden, Head Quarters, troops on Shenandoah Mountain, to Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 21 November 1862, 156; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter. Gen. R. E. Lee, Camp Fredericksburg, to Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 25 November 1862, 157; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Partial chronology of Gen. T. J. Jackson, 16 December 1862-15 May 1863, 158; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter. Gen. R. E. Lee, n. p., to Maj. Gen. A. P. Hill, n. p., 12 January 1863, 159; 2 pp.; Official copy probably sent to T. J. Jackson since it concerns the charges against A. P. Hill. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Consolidated report of the armament of 2nd Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, commanded by Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, 30 January 1863, 160; 1 p.
  - Letter. Thomas T. Munford, Moss Neck, to [____], 12 February 1863, 161; 8 pp.; Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Report on the condition of the transportation of the 2nd Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, 28 February 1863, 162; 1 p.
  - Battle report. Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., to Brig. Gen. R. H. Chilton, n. p., 7 March 1863, 163; 11 pp.; Battle of McDowell. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Copy of endorsement on Gen. A. P. Hill's report on the Battle of Cedar Run. 19 March 1863, 164; 2 pp.; Endorsed by Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter. Capt. Clifton H. Smith, Head Quarters, Dept. of South Carolina, Georgia and Florida, Charleston, South Carolina, to Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 6 April 1863, 165; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, 2nd Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, to Gen. S[amuel] Cooper, Adjutant and Inspector General, C. S. Army, n. p., 11 April 1863, 166; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, near Fredericksburg, to Gen. R. E. Lee, n. p., 15 April 1863, 167; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letter. Lt. Col. J. A. Robinson, Head Quarters, 25th Virginia Regiment, Shenandoah Mountains, to Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 16 April 1863, 168; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - [Battle report.] 27 April 1863, 169; 24 pp.; Writer and recipient unidentified. Written from Head Quarters, 2nd Corps, Army of Northern Virginia. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letter. Gen. R. E. Lee, Head Quarters, Army of Northern Virginia, to [Gen. T. J. Jackson], n. p., 30 April 1863, 170; 2 pp.; Also includes letter, 2 May 1863, from Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., to Gen. R. E. Lee, n. p. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letter. Capt. M[arcellus N. Moorman, Orange Court House, to Lt. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 10 May 1863, 171; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letter. "Extracts from a letter from Maj. Benjamin Watkins Leigh, 12 May 1863, 172; 16 pp. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Resolutions adopted by officers and men of the Stonewall Brigade on the occasion of General Jackson's death, 16 May 1863, 173; 4 pp.; Camp near Fredericksburg. Signed by C. A. Ronald, as president, and R. W. Hunter, as secretary. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Memorandum re: the Battle of McDowell, 17 May 1863, 174; 3 pp.; Probably in the handwriting of Maj. Robert L. Dabney. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letter. Secretary of War James A. Seddon, Richmond, to Robert L. Dabney, Hampden-Sidney, Virginia, 30 May 1863, 175; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter. George W. Jackson, Fancy Hills, Rockbridge County, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 27 June 1863, 176; 3 p. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter. Maj. W. J. Hawks, Orange Court House, to Major [R. L.] Dabney, n. p., 31 August 1863, 177; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter. Daniel B. Ewing, Gordonsville, to [____], 8 September 1863, 178; 18 pp.; Probably to R. L. Dabney. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. W. E. Jones, Rapidan Station, to R. L. Dabney, Hampden-Sidney, Virginia, 10 September 1863, 179; 12 pp.; Narrative of T. J. Jackson's career at West Point. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter. [Mary E. P. Allen?], Beaver Dam, to Judge [G. D.?] Camden, n. p., 12 September 1863, 180; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter. Anna M. Jackson, Cottage Home, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 19 September 1863, 181; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter. R. S. Ewell, n. p., to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 1 October 1863, 182; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter. Maj. [Wells J.] Hawks, Office Chief Commissary, 2nd Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, Orange Court House, to [R. L.] Dabney, n. p., 7 October 1863, 183; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter. J[oseph] G. Morrison, Camp of 57th N. C. Troops near Brandy Station, Virginia, to R. L. Dabney, Hampden-Sidney, Virginia, 29 October 1863, 184; 7 pp. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter. G. D. Camden, Brownsburg, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 21 November 1863, 185; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter. G. D. Camden, Brownsburg, to R. L. Dabney, Hampden-Sidney, Virginia, 25 November 1863, 186; 8 pp. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter. Francis McFarland, Rosemont, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 26 November 1863, 187; 2 pp.; With enclosures: Letter. T. J. Jackson, Winchester, to [Francis McFarland], n. p., 11 February 1862. Letter. T. J. Jackson, n. p., to [Francis McFarland], n. p., 31 July 1862. Letter. T. J. Jackson, Clarke County, to [Francis McFarland], n. p., 30 October 1862. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. W. H. C. Whiting, Wilmington, to Major R. L. Dabney, Hampden-Sidney, Virginia, 30 November 1863, 188; 5 pp. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter. G. D. Camden, Brownsburg, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 8 December 1863, 189; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter. Capt. R. E. Wilbourn, Head Quarters, 2nd Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 12 December 1863, 190; 20 pp. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter. Col. William J. Hoke, Lincolnton, North Carolina, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 31 December 1863, 191; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter. [Thomas T. Munford], Glen Alpine, Bedford, to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 31 December 1863, 192; 8 pp. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Receipts. For various provisions, 1864, 193; 6 pp. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. J. E. B. Stuart, Headquarters Cavalry Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, to Major H. W. Gilmore, n. p., 24 February 1864, 194; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. J. E. B. Stuart, Headquarters, Cavalry Corps, Army of Northern Virginia, n. p., to Major [H. W.] Gilmore, n. p., 29 February 1864, 195; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tax in kind. Form No. 2. Estimate No. 12. Charles W. Dabney, Hanover County, 22 December 1864, 196; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Richard Sterling, Greensboro, N. C., to R. L. Dabney, n. p., 1 January 1866, 197; 4 pp. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Willoughby Newton, "Linden", Hague P. O., Westmoreland County, to [R. L. Dabney?], n. p., June 1867, 198; 11 pp. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Dr. J. W. Bosworth in Philippi, West Virginia, to Roy B. Cook, in Charleston, West Virginia, 24 March 1929, 198a; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Picture. Mill in West Virginia owned by Gen. T. J. Jackson's uncle. n. d., 199; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Narrative. "Gen. [Jubal A.] Early's Narrative, Cedar Mountain," n. d., 200; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Narrative. "The Seven Days' Fighting about Richmond." n. d., 201; 15 pp.; By Hunter McGuire, Medical Director, 2nd Corps. Bears notation "Answer to Longstreet defending Jackson." (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Narrative. "Statement of Dr. [William J.?] Bland, Delegate from Lewis County, who married a daughter of John G. Jackson of Harrison County and Governor Meigs of Ohio," n. d., 202; 5 pp. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letter. Col. Thomas T. Munford, n. p., to Major [____] Hairston, n. p., n. d., 203; 8 pp. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Battle report. [Gen. T. J. Jackson], n. p., to Brig. Gen. R. H. Chilton, A. A. and Ins. Gen., Head Quarters, Department of Northern Virginia, n. p., n. d., 204; 18 pp.; "Report of the Battles of Cold Harbour and Malvern Hill by Lieut. Gen. T. J. Jackson." (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Narrative. "Maj. [Norvell] Cobb's Memorandum [re:] Jackson's Fall", n. d., 205; 4 pp. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Narrative. "Dr. [Hunter] McGuire's Narrative," n. d., 206; 8 pp. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Narrative. A. R. Boteler's Memoirs of T. J. Jackson, n. d., 207; 5 pp.; Apparently notes made by R. L. Dabney during a conversation with Boteler or from a letter written by Boteler. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Narrative re: Gen. T. J. Jackson. n. d., 208; 24 pp.; Probably by Dr. William S. White, Pastor of Presbyterian Church at Lexington, Virginia. It is possible that this narrative is actually portions of two different narratives. In the absence of the originals, or any list of items, it is not possible to establish identification beyond the notation on the page bearing pencil number 246. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Narrative re: Gen. T. J. Jackson. n. d., 209; 15 pp.; Possibly the narratives of Dr. Samuel B. Morrison, Lieut. James Power Smith and Maj. John A. Harman. In the absence of the originals or any list of items, it is not possible to establish positive identification of these narratives. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Narrative re: Gen. T. J. Jackson. "Rev. B[everly] Tucker Lacy's Narrative." n. d., 210; 17 pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Narrative. "The Fall of Jackson." n. d., 211; 4 pp.; Major Arthur L. Rogers, Chaffin's Bluff, to [R. L.] Dabney, n. p. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Narrative. "Jackson as a Military Man." n. d., 212; 4 pp.; No further identification possible. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Col. J. W. Allen, n. p., to Capt. R. J. Wingate, A. A. G., n. p., n. d., 213; 4 pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Map. "Pencil Sketch for Battle of Gaines' Mill made by R. L. Dabney." n. d., 214; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Epitaph. "In memoriam:" by John Dimitry of New Orleans, n. d., 215; 1 p.; Insciption for Jackson monument in Richmond. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Schedule for Method of Conducting Elections to be held on the Fourth Thursday in May. n. d., 216; 1 pp.; Signed by John L. Eubank, Secretary of the Commonwealth, Filed as having no date. With unidentified newspaper clipping attached. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum. Unidentified, n. d., 217; 2 pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Message. Gen. R. E. Lee, n. p., to Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., n. d., 218; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Capt. John T. Wingfield, n. p., to Col. [____] Ashby, n. p., n. d., 219; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notices of the military services of Brevet Major T[homas] J. Jackson, 1st Regiment of Artillery, from the reports of the several generals under whose notice he came in the Valley of Mexico, n. d., 220; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Narrative. "Last Days - Mrs. Jackson's Narrative." n. d., 221; 4 pp. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Excerpt. From "History of the 5th West Virginia Cavalry, formerly the 2nd Virginia Infantry, and of Battery G, First West Virginia Light Artillery" by Frank S. Reader. n. d., 222; 1 p.; Page 135 of the document. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Notes. T. J. Jackson's notes for one of his reports, n. d., 223; 1 p. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings. Concerning T. J. Jackson from unidentified sources, n. d., 224; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Narratives. Unidentified, n. d., 225; 7 pp. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous. Unidentified, n. d., 226; 3 pp. (Box 2, Folder 5)